These English & Foreign subtitles created by ZoowlCZ (ver. 2024-10) are an expanded version of the English subtitles created by Bokutox of YIFY-TORRENTS (Torporr of Outland PVP (EU)).
You may go no further.
You will not enter Gondor.
Who are you to deny us passage?
Legolas...
...fire a warning shot
past the bosun's ear.
Mind your aim.
That's it. Right. We warned you.
Prepare to be boarded.
Boarded?
By you and whose army?
This army.
In there.
What is this place?
Master must go inside the tunnel.
Now that I'm here, I don't think I want to.
It's the only way.
Go in...
...or go back.
I can't go back.
- What's that smell?
- Orcses' filth.
Orcses come in here sometimes.
Hurry.
This way.
Smeagol?
Over here.
It's sticky. What is it?
You will see.
Oh, yes.
Smeagol?
Smeagol!
Sam.
And you, Frodo Baggins...
I give you the light of
Earendil, our most beloved star.
May it be a light for you in dark places...
...when all other lights go out.
[Quenya] Aiya Eärendil, Elenion Ancalima!
[English] Hail Eärendil, Brightest of the Stars!
Naughty little fly.
Why does he cry?
Caught in a web
Soon you'll be...
Eaten.
Got away, did it, precious?
Not this time.
- Not this time!
- No!
It wasn't us. It wasn't us!
Smeagol wouldn't hurt master.
We promised.
You must believe us.
It was the precious.
The precious made us do it.
I have to destroy it, Smeagol.
I have to destroy it for both our sakes.
No!
I'm so sorry, Sam.
I'm so sorry.
This task was appointed to you...
...Frodo of the Shire.
If you do not find a way...
...no one will.
The scouts report Minas
Tirith is surrounded.
The lower level's in flames.
Everywhere, legions of the enemy advance.
Time is against us.
Make ready!
Take heart, Merry.
It will soon be over.
My lady...
...you are fair and brave...
...and have much to live for...
...and many who love you.
I know it is too late to turn aside.
I know there is not much
point now in hoping.
If I were a knight of Rohan...
...capable of great deeds, but...
...I'm not.
I'm a Hobbit.
And I know I can't save Middle-earth.
I just want to help my friends.
Frodo.
Sam.
Pippin.
More than anything, I wish
I could see them again.
Prepare to move out!
Make haste. We ride through the night.
To battle.
Back to the gate!
Hurry!
I am steward of the House of Anarion.
Thus have I walked.
And thus now will I sleep.
Gondor is lost.
There is no hope for Men.
Why do the fools fly?
Better to die sooner than late.
For die we must.
No tomb for Denethor and Faramir.
No long, slow sleep of death embalmed.
We shall burn, like the
heathen kings of old.
Bring wood and oil.
Steady.
You are soldiers of Gondor.
No matter what comes through that
gate, you will stand your ground.
Run!
Volley!
Fire!
Let him go, you filth.
Let him go!
You will not touch him again.
Come on and finish it.
Back!
Mr. Frodo.
Oh, no.
Frodo.
Mr. Frodo.
Wake up.
Don't leave me here alone.
Don't go where I can't follow.
Wake up.
Not asleep.
Dead.
You get back, you scum!
What's this?
Looks like old Shelob's
been having a bit of fun.
Killed another one, has she?
No.
This fellow ain't dead.
Not dead?
- She jabs him with her stinger,
and he goes as limp as a boned fish.
Then she has her way with them.
That's how she likes to feed.
Fresh blood.
Get him to the tower!
Samwise, you fool.
This scum will be awake
in a couple of hours.
Then he'll wish he'd never been born.
The house of his spirit crumbles.
He is burning.
Already burning.
He's not dead.
He's not dead!
No! No!
- Farewell, Peregrin, son of Paladin.
- No! No! No!
I release you from my service.
Go now and die in what
way seems best to you.
Pour oil on the wood!
Come on, soldier! Move it!
Hurry along there! Hurry along!
Gandalf!
Where is Gandalf?
Retreat!
The city is breached!
Fall back!
To the second level!
Get the women and children out!
Get them out!
Retreat!
Come on. Come on, move.
Move into the city.
Kill all in your path.
Take them down!
Fight!
Fight to the last man!
Fight for your lives!
Gandalf!
Denethor has lost his mind!
He's burning Faramir alive!
Up! Quickly!
Go back to the abyss.
Fall into the nothingness that
awaits you and your master.
Do you not know death when
you see it, old man?
This is my hour.
Gandalf!
You have failed.
The world of Men will fall.
Courage, Merry.
Courage for our friends.
Form ranks, you maggots. Form ranks!
Pikes in front. Archers behind.
Eomer, take your Eored down the left flank.
Flank ready.
Gamling, follow the king's
banner down the center.
Grimbold, take your company
right after you pass the wall.
Forth, and fear no darkness!
Arise!
Arise Riders of Theoden!
Spears shall be shaken!
Shields shall be splintered!
A sword-day!
A red day!
Ere the sun rises!
Whatever happens, stay with me.
I'll look after you.
Ride now!
Ride!
Ride for ruin!
And the world's ending!
- Death!
For Eorlingas!
Fire!
Death!
Charge!
Fire at will!
Set a fire in our flesh.
Stay this madness!
You may triumph in the
field of battle for a day...
...but against the power
that has risen in the east...
...there is no victory.
No!
You will not take my son from me!
Faramir.
So passes Denethor, son of Ecthelion.
Drive them to the river!
Make safe the city!
Re-form the line!
Sound the charge!
Take them head-on!
Charge!
Cut him down!
Take the reins.
Pull him left!
Left!
Aim for their heads!
Bring it down! Bring it down!
Bring it down!
Merry!
I didn't think it would end this way.
End?
No, the journey doesn't end here.
Death is just another path...
...one that we all must take.
The grey rain curtain
of this world rolls back...
...and all turns to silver glass.
And then you see it.
What, Gandalf?
See what?
White shores...
...and beyond.
A far green country...
...under a swift sunrise.
Well...
...that isn't so bad.
No.
No, it isn't.
Rally to me!
To me!
Feast on his flesh.
I will kill you if you touch him.
Do not come between the Nazgul
and his prey.
Late as usual!
Pirate scum!
There's knife-work here needs doing.
Come on, you sea rats! Get off your ships!
There's plenty for the both of us.
May the best Dwarf win.
You fool.
No man can kill me.
Die now.
I am no man.
- 15! 16!
- 17!
Merry!
Legolas!
33.
34.
That still only counts as one!
Come on, then. Come on!
I know your face...
Eowyn.
My eyes darken.
No.
I am going to save you.
You already did.
Eowyn...
...my body is broken.
You have to let me go.
I go to my fathers...
...in whose mighty company...
I shall not now feel ashamed.
Eowyn.
Release us.
Bad idea.
Very handy in a
tight spot, these lads.
Despite the
fact they're dead.
You gave us your word.
I hold your oath fulfilled.
Go.
Be at peace.
Merry.
No!
♫ With a sigh. ♫
♫ You turn away. ♫
♫ With a deepening heart. ♫
♫ No more words to say. ♫
♫ You will find. ♫
♫That the world has changed forever. ♫
♫ And the trees are now turning
from green to gold. ♫
♫ And the sun is now fading. ♫
♫ I wish I could hold you closer. ♫
Merry!
Merry.
Merry, it's me.
It's Pippin.
I knew you'd find me.
Yes.
Are you going to leave me?
No, Merry.
I'm going to look after you.
Hands off!
That shiny shirt, that's mine.
It's going to the Great Eye,
along with everything else.
I don't take orders from
stinking Morgul-rats!
You touch it, and I'll stick
this blade in your gut.
The scum tried to knife me.
Kill him!
That's for Frodo!
And for the Shire!
And that's for my old Gaffer!
Stop your squealing, you dunghill rat.
I'm gonna bleed you...
...like a stuck pig.
Not if I stick you first.
Sam!
Oh, Sam, I'm so sorry.
Sorry for everything.
- Let's get you out of here.
- It's too late.
It's over.
They've taken it.
Sam...
...they took the Ring.
Begging your pardon, but they haven't.
I thought I'd lost you.
So I took it.
Only for safekeeping.
Give it to me.
Give me the Ring, Sam.
Sam.
Give me the Ring.
You must understand.
The Ring is my burden.
It will destroy you, Sam.
Come on, Mr. Frodo.
We best find you some clothes.
You can't go walking through
Mordor in naught but your skin.
We did it, Mr. Frodo.
We made it to Mordor.
There are so many of them.
We'll never get through unseen.
It's him...
...the Eye.
We have to go in there, Mr. Frodo.
There's nothing for it.
Come on.
Let's just make it down the hill
for starters.
Frodo has passed beyond my sight.
The darkness is deepening.
If Sauron had the Ring, we would know it.
It's only a matter of time.
He has suffered a defeat, yes but...
...behind the walls of Mordor,
our enemy is regrouping.
Let him stay there.
Let him rot!
Why should we care?
Because 10,000 Orcs now stand
between Frodo and Mount Doom.
I've sent him to his death.
No.
There is still hope for Frodo.
He needs time and safe passage
across the plains of Gorgoroth.
We can give him that.
How?
Draw out Sauron's armies.
Empty his lands.
Then we gather our full strength
and march on the Black Gate.
We cannot achieve victory
through strength of arms.
Not for ourselves.
But we can give Frodo his chance if
we keep Sauron's Eye fixed upon us.
Keep him blind to all else that moves.
A diversion.
Certainty of death...
...small chance of success...
What are we waiting for?
Sauron will suspect a trap.
He will not take the bait.
Oh, I think he will.
Long have you hunted me.
Long have I eluded you.
No more.
Behold the Sword of Elendil.
The city has fallen silent.
There is no warmth left in the sun.
It grows so cold.
It's just the damp of
the first spring rain.
I do not believe this darkness will endure.
Look, the Orcs...
they're moving off.
You see, Mr. Frodo...
some luck at last.
Move it, you slugs!
Come on!
Faster!
Come along, you coldhearted
wretched scum...
I'll whip you down to the bone, you...
Come on!
What have I told you?
No evation...
Now move it!
Get up!
Come on, you slugs!
You two are going straight
to the front line!
Now, move it! Go on! Fall
in! Move it! Move it! Move it!
To the Gate, you slugs!
Now, move it!
Don't you know we're at war?
Company!
Halt!
Inspection!
Sam...
...help me.
Mr. Frodo!
Stand up, Mr. Frodo.
Stand up!
It's so heavy.
Oh, no.
What do...
What do we do?
- Hit me.
- What?
Hit me, Sam. Start fighting.
Get off of me!
Nobody pushes me, you filthy maggot.
Break it up! Break it up!
Oi!
I'll have your guts if you don't
shut this rabble down!
Go, Sam.
Now!
Move along, scum!
Back in the line!
You maggots!
Get back into the line, you slugs!
Dig it, you slugs. Move it.
I can't...
...I can't manage the Ring, Sam.
It's... It's...
It's such a weight to carry.
It's...
...such a weight.
We're going that way.
Straight as we can.
There's no point carrying
anything we're not sure to need.
Mr. Frodo.
Look.
There is light...
...and beauty up there...
...that no shadow can touch.
Take mine.
There's a few drops left.
There will be none left
for the return journey.
I don't think there will be
a return journey, Mr. Frodo.
[Black Speech]  Kelkum-ishi.
[English]  In the coldness.
Frodo, get down!
Hide!
Frodo!
Where are they?
Let the Lord of the Black Land come forth!
Let justice be done upon him!
My master, Sauron the Great,
bids thee welcome.
Is there any in this rout with
authority to treat with me?
We do not come to treat with Sauron...
...faithless...
...and accursed.
Tell your master this:
The armies of Mordor must disband.
He is to depart these lands,
never to return.
Old Greybeard.
I have a token I was bidden to show thee.
Frodo.
Silence.
No!
Silence!
The Halfling was dear to thee, I see.
Know that he suffered greatly
at the hands of his host.
Who would've thought one so small...
...could endure so much pain?
And he did, Gandalf.
He did.
And who is this?
Isildur's heir?
It takes more to make a king
than a broken Elvish blade.
I guess that concludes negotiations.
I do not believe it.
I will not.
[Black Speech]  Ash nazg durb!
[English]  One Ring to rule!
Pull back.
Pull back!
[Black Speech]  Ash nazg durb!
[English]  One Ring to rule!
It's gone, Mr. Frodo.
The light's passed on,
away towards the north.
Something's drawn its gaze.
[Black Speech]  Ash nazg durb!
[English]  One Ring to rule!
Hold your ground! Hold your ground.
Sons of Gondor!
Of Rohan!
My brothers!
I see in your eyes...
...the same fear that would
take the heart of me.
A day may come...
...when the courage of Men fails...
...when we forsake our friends and
break all bonds of fellowship.
But it is not this day.
An hour of wolves...
...and shattered shields...
...when the age of Men comes crashing down.
But it is not this day.
This day we fight!
By all that you hold dear...
...on this good earth...
I bid you stand!
Men of the West!
Never thought I'd die fighting
side by side with an Elf.
What about side by side with a friend?
Aye.
I could do that.
Do you remember the Shire, Mr. Frodo?
It'll be spring soon.
And the orchards will be in blossom.
And the birds will be nesting
in the hazel thicket.
And they'll be sowing the summer
barley in the lower fields...
...and eating the first of
the strawberries with cream.
Do you remember the taste of strawberries?
No, Sam.
I can't recall the taste of food...
...nor the...
...the sound of water...
...touch of grass.
I'm...
...naked in the dark.
There's...
...there's nothing.
No veil...
...between me...
...and the wheel of fire.
I can see him...
...with my waking eyes.
Then let us be rid of it...
...once and for all.
Come on, Mr. Frodo.
I can't carry it for you...
...but I can carry you.
Come on!
Aragorn.
Elessar.
For Frodo.
Look, Mr. Frodo.
A doorway.
We're almost there.
Clever Hobbits to climb so high!
Mustn't go that way.
Mustn't hurt the precious.
You swore!
You swore on the precious!
Smeagol promised!
Smeagol lied.
Frodo!
Eagles.
The eagles are coming!
Frodo!
I'm here, Sam.
Destroy it!
Go on!
Now!
Throw it in the fire!
What are you waiting for?
Just let it go!
The Ring is mine.
No.
No!
Yes!
Precious!
Precious! Precious!
Give me your hand!
Take my hand!
No!
Don't you let go.
Don't let go.
Reach!
Frodo!
It's gone.
It's done.
Yes, Mr. Frodo.
It's over now.
I can see the Shire.
The Brandywine River.
Bag End.
Gandalf's fireworks.
The lights...
...in the Party Tree.
Rosie Cotton dancing.
She had ribbons in her hair.
If ever I was to marry someone...
it would've been her.
It would've been her.
I'm glad to be with you, Samwise Gamgee...
...here at the end of all things.
Gandalf?
Frodo!
Gimli!
Now come the days of the king.
May they be blessed.
This day does not belong to one man...
...but to all.
Let us together rebuild this world...
...that we may share in the days of peace.
[Quenya] ♫ Et Eärello... ♫
[English] ♫ Out of the Great Sea... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...Endorenna utúlien. ♫
[English] ♫ ...to Middle-earth I am come. ♫
[Quenya] ♫ Sinome maruvan... ♫
[English] ♫ In this place I will abide... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...ar Hildinyar... ♫
[English] ♫ ...and my heirs... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...tenn’ Ambar-metta. ♫
[English] ♫ ...unto the World-ending. ♫
[Sindarin] Hannon le.
[English] Thank you.
[Sindarin] ♫ Tinúviel... ♫
[English] ♫ Tinúviel... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ...elvanui... ♫
[English] ♫ ...the elven-fair... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ...elleth alfirin edhelhael. ♫
[English] ♫ ...immortal maiden elven-wise. ♫
My friends...
...you bow to no one.
And thus it was.
A Fourth Age of Middle-earth began.
And the Fellowship of the Ring...
...though eternally bound by friendship...
...and love...
...was ended.
Thirteen months to the day...
...since Gandalf sent us on
our long journey...
...we found ourselves looking
upon a familiar sight.
We were home.
Hi.
Hey, watch the pumpkin.
More of the same, Rosie.
Good night, lads.
How do you pick up the threads
of an old life?
How do you go on...
when... in your heart...
...you begin to understand...
...there is no going back?
There are some things
that time cannot mend...
...some hurts that go too deep...
...that have taken hold.
Mr. Frodo?
What is it?
It's been four years to the
day since Weathertop, Sam.
It's never really healed.
"There and Back Again." A Hobbit's tale
by Bilbo Baggins.
And "The Lord of the Rings"
by Frodo Baggins.
You finished it.
Not quite.
There's room for a little more.
Bilbo once told me..
...his part in this tale would end...
...that each of us must come
and go in the telling.
Bilbo's story was now over.
There would be no more journeys for him...
...save one.
Tell me again, lad...
...where are we going?
To the harbor, Bilbo.
The Elves have accorded
you a special honor...
...a place on the last ship
to leave Middle-earth.
Frodo...
...any chance of seeing that old
Ring of mine again?
The one I gave you.
I'm sorry, Uncle.
I'm afraid I lost it.
Oh.
Pity.
I should like to have
held it one last time.
Well, here's a sight I
have never seen before.
The power of the Three Rings is ended.
The time has come...
for the dominion of Men.
[Sindarin] I Aear cân ven na mar.
[English] The sea calls us to home.
I think I'm...
...quite ready for another adventure.
Farewell...
...my brave Hobbits.
My work is now finished.
Here at last...
...on the shores of the sea...
...comes the end of our Fellowship.
I will not say, "Do not weep"...
...for not all tears are an evil.
It is time, Frodo.
What does he mean?
We set out to save the Shire, Sam.
And it has been saved.
But not for me.
You don't mean that.
You can't leave.
The last pages are for you, Sam.
My dear Sam
You cannot always be torn in two.
You will have to be one and
whole for many years.
You have so much to enjoy
and to be and to do.
Your part in the story will go on.
Well...
I'm back.
...into the west.